<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Joshua Milas</title>
    <link>https://DeepHorizons.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Joshua Milas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 22:50:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://DeepHorizons.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter in the classroom</title>
      <link>https://deephorizons.github.io/2016/06/06/jupyter-in-the-classroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 22:50:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deephorizons.github.io/2016/06/06/jupyter-in-the-classroom/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I learned about &lt;a href=&#34;https://jupyter.org&#34;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt;,
a web based &amp;lsquo;notebook&amp;rsquo; editor that allows for both documentation and code.
I soon found
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.rackspace.com/blog/deploying-jupyterhub-for-education/&#34;&gt;Jessica Hamrick&amp;rsquo;s post on rackspace&lt;/a&gt;
describing her usage of Jupyter for a class she taught.
This is what sparked my research into it,
and my journey to attempt to incorporate it into the
Computer Engineering Curiculum at RIT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;background:2c2d9417caacf30ec48e6775db67b5c1&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never liked doing programing on paper.
There is a certain benefit in being able to work out a problem without your
favorite editor,
but in the academic setting it&amp;rsquo;s less of programming and more of
&amp;lsquo;can you express this idea in a very specific way?&amp;rsquo;.
I always slogged through programing assignments that needed to be handed in,
just to be told that I missed a semi-colon
or that my curly brackets didn&amp;rsquo;t look right.
There have been two attempts made at RIT to allow students to submit code over
the Internet, &lt;code&gt;try&lt;/code&gt; and MyCourses.
&lt;code&gt;try&lt;/code&gt; has the problem of being super particular to the output of your submitted
program that even an extra space might give you a failing mark.
MyCourses was never made for programming, so submitting assignments is just a
matter of zipping up your assignment and hoping the grader has a similar
environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;jupyter-in-the-classroom:2c2d9417caacf30ec48e6775db67b5c1&#34;&gt;Jupyter in the classroom&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats where Jupyter comes in.
Notebooks are supposed to be portable, made to be shared among people.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jupyterhub/jupyterhub&#34;&gt;JupyterHub&lt;/a&gt;
allows Jupyter to be run on a central server, removing setup from the end user
and giving everyone access to the same environment.
You are guaranteed that if it runs for you, it will run for everyone else too.
There is also &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jupyter/nbgrader&#34;&gt;nbgrader&lt;/a&gt;,
which allows teachers to create assignments, distribute them to students,
and collect them.
It also has autograding features, but unlike &lt;code&gt;try&lt;/code&gt; the students
have access to the tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt Jupyter was a good tool to use.
It easily integrates the documentation and code,
enabling a step by step process that is somewhat impractical in
traditional reports.
The documentation is easily written in markdown,
and the document can be downloaded as a LaTex formatted document.
This enables people to use Jupyter even if the class isn&amp;rsquo;t
using it specifically.
Notebooks are also interactive, showing the results right then and there.
Teachers could use notebooks to show live examples in class,
rather than show code in a presentation and talk about it.
Jupyter also supports many languages,
well beyond the original language of Python.
In particular it supports MATLAB, a language used extensively by engineers
and in many classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this information, I wanted to see if it could actually work for a class
that was not designed to use it.
My objectives were to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out if Jupyter was flexible enough to adapt to classes not even aware
of its existence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out if it was intuitive enough for students to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore nbgrader and other plugins to enable teachers to use
Jupyter for assignments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test my theory on its benefits of it in the academic environment,
last semester I worked with a teacher and attempted to do every
assignment, project, and homework in the class in Jupyter.
It was a Digital Signal Processing class.
The assignment and projects were done in MATLAB,
with a few homework problems from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;setup:2c2d9417caacf30ec48e6775db67b5c1&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to request a server from my department with
the specification that I needed.
I decided to run JupyterHub in a Linux container using LXD so that I could take
snapshots and restore them in the event something went wrong.
I used NGINX to proxy all web requests to the container.
I also used NGINX to enable HTTPS (Rather than do it on Jupyters end)
JupyterHub defaults to use Linux user accounts for authentication,
which was fine in this case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just so happened that there is a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/calysto/matlab_kernel&#34;&gt;MATLAB kernel&lt;/a&gt; for Jupyter.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to deal with licensing,
so I rewrote the assignments as I got them to work with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/octave/&#34;&gt;Octave&lt;/a&gt;,
an open source alternative to MATLAB.
There also happened to be an
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/calysto/octave_kernel&#34;&gt;Octave kernel&lt;/a&gt; which is what I used.
When I installed Octave, I also installed all of its libraries as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our class also use a library produced by the book author named &lt;code&gt;spfirst&lt;/code&gt;.
This library was made for MATLAB and did not work with Octave.
I ported this library to work with both,
available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DeepHorizons/spfirst&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my spelling is atrocious, I also decided to install a spell checker.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/ipre/calico&#34;&gt;Calico&lt;/a&gt; is the one I used.&lt;br /&gt;
(&lt;code&gt;NOTE:&lt;/code&gt; Their website is down, the following steps can be taken to install it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jupyter nbextension install https://bitbucket.org/ipre/calico/downloads/calico-spell-check-1.0.zip
jupyter nbextension enable calico-spell-check
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Calysto/notebook-extensions&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Calysto/notebook-extensions&lt;/a&gt; which hosts some
other extensions.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I installed pandoc and LaTeX so that the notebooks could be downloaded
as PDFs.
LaTex and all of its packages were installed to ensure compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;results:2c2d9417caacf30ec48e6775db67b5c1&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The test was mostly successful.
Out of the two projects, I did the first 100% in Jupyter.
The second could have been done in Jupyter,
but would involve downloading, many file uploads, and playing audio,
things that Jupyter isn&amp;rsquo;t good at yet.
All but one assignment was done in Jupyter.
The one that wasn&amp;rsquo;t needed a specific MATLAB tool
that is not available in Octave.
Homework was practical to do in Jupyter until graphs and charts had to be drawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very nice being able to include graphs and plots so easily.
I could execute a small piece of code, explain it, then execute some more.
The document flow was unlike a traditional report where the code is in
the appendix, being explained earlier in the paper.
The reports I made did not distinguish the sections between design and results.
A teacher may not like this combination, but it is very well possible to
make this distinction, I just felt it worked better in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for my objectives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out if Jupyter was flexible enough to adapt to classes not even aware
of its existence

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jupyter is definitely flexible enough to be used for nearly any class that
has a coding requirement. I even used it for assignments in other classes
that didnt have coding because it was easier to write in markdown than
in LaTex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some special care must be taken to assure that any report made meets the
departments requirements for a standard lab report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out if it was intuitive enough for students to use

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I believe that Jupyter is intuitive enough for the average student.
I had some other students try it out, once they got past the initial
questions, they were able to pick it right up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloading files is interesting. A file that Jupyter can open must be
downloaded using &lt;code&gt;File-&amp;gt;Download&lt;/code&gt; rather than right clicking and
downloading. All other files are downloaded by right clicking and
downloading. This may be unintuitive and cause some problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot play sounds through a notebook. This was quite critical
in this class. The workaround was to have the notebook generate a sound
file, and then access it via the browser and play it.
This is not ideal and this should be investigated to find a better solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore nbgrader and other plugins to enable teachers to use
Jupyter for assignments

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currently there is no web UI for interfacing with nbgrader,
everything must be done via the command line.
This is inconvenient for teachers who are not familiar with Linux.
In my testing I made a few helper scripts but that can only go so far.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The autograding feature works by having a box for implementation,
then several tests. If the tests fail, then the points are not awarded.
But the tests are always visible to the students.
This disallows usages where you would not want teh student to see the tests
line in a simple question you would see from other web based quizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;next-steps:2c2d9417caacf30ec48e6775db67b5c1&#34;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next steps is to move my single user instance and allow the department
to use it.
This means using a different authentication method other than the user accounts.
Our school uses Shibboleth as its primary authentication system.
Apache has a &lt;code&gt;mod_shib&lt;/code&gt; plugin that would allow a near drop in.
There is then a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cwaldbieser/jhub_remote_user_authenticator&#34;&gt;JupyterHub authenticator&lt;/a&gt;
than can use the data to handle the rest.
(More can be read &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jupyterhub/jupyterhub/issues/332&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point is security and files.
No student should be able to see or access another students files.
This can be accomplished by using Docker and containers.
Docker can be used to spin up the instance of Jupyter for each student.
Their files can then be linked using NFS or Samba.
This also helps with distribution, as one server can only handle about 30
students from what I have read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other two steps are student adoption and professor adoption.
For this to be successful, the end goal is to have students use this to
make their lives easier.
If the students do not use it, then there is no point.
I believe that some students will gravitate twards using this.
It is simple enough to get started and has a lot of potential for helping.
Once students begin to use it,
professors could then start to use it for their class.
It could start with them giving in class examples, making notebooks available
for the students to look at.
Once professors are comfortable with Jupyter, they may then begin using it
for assignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The targeted classes in my department are the Digital Signal Processing,
Assembly, and Applied Programming (which uses C).
Octave is already supported by Jupyer and there is a kernel for running
C/C++.
At the time there is no assembly interpreter for ARM
which is what the class uses.
I am current writing an interpreter to be used in the class with hopes of
releasing a beta in a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Kaldi on Windows: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://deephorizons.github.io/2016/02/20/building-kaldi-on-windows-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 10:35:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deephorizons.github.io/2016/02/20/building-kaldi-on-windows-part-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is a multi part series about building Kaldi on Windows with Microsoft Visual Studio 2015&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:
I have submitted pull requests to update the build process for MSVS2015
and it is now in the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;speech-recognition:008c93024a31de39f86ab9e8c9e70af4&#34;&gt;Speech Recognition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like others, I have always been interested in adding speech recognition to my projects.
When I first heard about &lt;a href=&#34;http://cmusphinx.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;CMU Sphinx&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&#34;http://julius.osdn.jp/en_index.php&#34;&gt;Julius&lt;/a&gt;
I quickly jumped to learn them and integrate them into my project.
It mostly lead to a fruitless result, mostly because I was young and ignorant,
but partly because the tools were just not the most accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last attempt was to build a bot for a Mumble server,
sitting in the lounge listening for keywords so that it could report back
some useful information.
For example, if you asked it &amp;ldquo;Whats the weather like?&amp;rdquo;
It would respond with
&amp;ldquo;The current weather is partly cloudy with a temperature of 56 degrees&amp;rdquo;.
When I started I tried to use Julius, but this was fruitless for reasons which I cannot remember.
The next attempt was to use Sphinx.
This proved to be more useful, there was already &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cmusphinx/pocketsphinx-python&#34;&gt;a python library&lt;/a&gt;
And they provide &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/cmusphinx/files/Acoustic%20and%20Language%20Models/US%20English%20Generic%20Acoustic%20Model/&#34;&gt;models&lt;/a&gt;
So that you can just hit the ground running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After tinkering around, fixing bugs, and figuring out how to get it all set up,
it did in fact work.
The problem?
It couldn&amp;rsquo;t get my speech correct.
It would get a close approximate, but never enough to determined what I said.
The solution to this was to use a keyword file,
A list of phrases and a probability level to limit what Sphinx would recognize
(called Out-of-Grammar rejection).
This was fine for a small project with a limited domain of possible inputs,
like days of the week or specific phrases for certain actions,
but this would never be suitable for anything larger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;kaldi:008c93024a31de39f86ab9e8c9e70af4&#34;&gt;Kaldi&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thats when I heard about &lt;a href=&#34;http://kaldi-asr.org/&#34;&gt;Kaldi&lt;/a&gt;.
Kaldi is the &amp;lsquo;Next Gen&amp;rsquo; of speech recognition.
Developed in 2011 as a research project, it uses current modern technology and algorithms
to achieve speech recognition that&amp;rsquo;s leaps and bounds better than the current alternatives.
Kaldi is also designed to be loosely coupled,
making it easy to switch in newer technology or algorithms as they become available
(&lt;a href=&#34;http://kaldi-asr.org/doc/online_programs.html&#34;&gt;which has already happened&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why hasn&amp;rsquo;t everyone switched over to Kaldi?
Because it nearly requires a PHD to use it.
It is very much still a research project,
and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://kaldi-asr.org/doc/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; isnt quite up to par for the average person.
There are efforts to revise the documentation to enable ease of use,
but it is still far from being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckly a lot of the heavy lifting has been done.
Tanel Alum has made a gstreamer plugin that takes audio from an input file and pipes it into kaldi.
It is not yet in the kaldi source, and therefor must be compiled separetely.
He has already made a server that accepts websocket requests.
If you just want to use that, you get get it
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alumae/kaldi-gstreamer-server&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;,
or get it as a docker container
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jcsilva/docker-kaldi-gstreamer-server&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-compile-on-windows:008c93024a31de39f86ab9e8c9e70af4&#34;&gt;Why compile on Windows?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because thats what I use for my everyday development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prereqs:008c93024a31de39f86ab9e8c9e70af4&#34;&gt;Prereqs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows 7 x64&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/downloads/download-visual-studio-vs.aspx&#34;&gt;Microsoft Visual Studio Community 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/download/win&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will also need to apply patches.
I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://msys2.github.io/&#34;&gt;MSYS2&lt;/a&gt;, but it is not required.
Look up &lt;a href=&#34;http://gnuwin32.sourceforge.net/packages/patch.htm&#34;&gt;Patch for Windows&lt;/a&gt;.
In the examples I use &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt; and other command line tools,
but you can do the actions manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaldi had some instructions for building on windows located &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kaldi-asr/kaldi/blob/master/windows/INSTALL.md&#34;&gt;In the windows folder&lt;/a&gt;
from which much of this is derived.
Read that for the most up to date install steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is good to note here that we will be building a 64 bit version of Kaldi
and of all the tools.
You may try for the 32 bit version, but you will have to pick the correct download
for the tools (namely OpenBlas, Win32-int32).
I have not tried this, so YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-the-stuff:008c93024a31de39f86ab9e8c9e70af4&#34;&gt;Getting the stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to clone the repo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/kaldi-asr/kaldi.git kaldi
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cd into the tools directory and checkout the windows version of
&lt;a href=&#34;http://openfst.org&#34;&gt;OpenFst&lt;/a&gt;.
Kaldi &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be compile with 1.4.x, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work on windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd kaldi/tools
git clone https://github.com/jtrmal/openfstwin-1.3.4.git openfst
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to get pthread-win32 as well.
Download
&lt;a href=&#34;http://downloads.sourceforge.net/project/pthreads4w/pthreads-w32-2-9-1-release.zip&#34;&gt;http://downloads.sourceforge.net/project/pthreads4w/pthreads-w32-2-9-1-release.zip&lt;/a&gt;
and unzip it into a folder named &lt;code&gt;pthreads&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget http://downloads.sourceforge.net/project/pthreads4w/pthreads-w32-2-9-1-release.zip
mkdir pthreads
cd pthreads
unzip ../pthreads-w32-2-9-1-release.zip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, you need a BLAS package.
I recommend OpenBlas as it is free,
but Kaldi supports MLK as well.
If you do use OpenBlas, you need the minwg dll as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ..
wget http://sourceforge.net/projects/openblas/files/v0.2.14/OpenBLAS-v0.2.14-Win64-int32.zip
wget http://sourceforge.net/projects/openblas/files/v0.2.14/mingw64_dll.zip
unzip OpenBLAS-v0.2.14-Win64-int32.zip
unzip mingw64_dll.zip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;patches:008c93024a31de39f86ab9e8c9e70af4&#34;&gt;Patches&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patches need to be applied to OpenFst and pthreads&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd openfst
patch -p1 &amp;lt; ../extras/openfstwin-1.3.4.patch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pthreads need a patch because of MSVS 2015 will throw an error if &lt;code&gt;timespec&lt;/code&gt; is redefined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ../pthreads
patch -p1 &amp;lt; ../extras/pthread-2.9.1.patch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building:008c93024a31de39f86ab9e8c9e70af4&#34;&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First step is to build OpenFst.
Open the solution in the latest MSVCnn folder and compile it under &lt;code&gt;Release&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;x64&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After it has successfully compiled, we need to modify the &lt;code&gt;variable.props&lt;/code&gt; file
under &lt;code&gt;kaldi/windows&lt;/code&gt;.
Modify the &lt;code&gt;OPENBLAS&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;PTHREADW&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;OPENFST&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;OPENFSTLIB&lt;/code&gt; values.
Use the absolute path and make sure to keep the folder the same.
Use the current values as a reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also need to delete the &lt;code&gt;kaldiwin.props&lt;/code&gt; file and reaname &lt;code&gt;kaldiwin_openblas.props&lt;/code&gt;
to &lt;code&gt;kaldiwin.props&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kaldi solution is ready to be built.
Use the perl script &lt;code&gt;generate_solution.pl&lt;/code&gt; with the appropriate arguments.
We will be using &lt;code&gt;--enable-openblas&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;vs2015&lt;/code&gt; as the version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;perl generate_solution.pl --vsver vs2015 --enable-openblas
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will create a folder named &lt;code&gt;kaldiwin_vs2015_OPENBLAS&lt;/code&gt;
in the root of the kaldi directory.
Open the solution file in it and change the project to &lt;code&gt;Release&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;x64&lt;/code&gt;.
Then simply go to &lt;code&gt;Build &amp;gt; Build Solution&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, the build is going to take a while.
Go make a bowl of popcorn and watch a movie.
And if everything went alright, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a fully working compiled version
of Kaldi.
A few projects will have failed, in particular the &lt;code&gt;online&lt;/code&gt; projects.
These projects rely on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.portaudio.com/&#34;&gt;PortAudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, you should have all of the binaries for Kaldi.
As you might see, Kaldi is not just one binary, but a collection.
The &lt;code&gt;egs&lt;/code&gt; folder contains &amp;lsquo;recipes&amp;rsquo;, or collections of scripts use to train
and test those models.
Look at those to get an idea of how everything works.
In particular, the &lt;code&gt;egs/fisher_english/s5&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;egs/voxforge/gst_demo&lt;/code&gt;.
If it&amp;rsquo;s all very confusing, don&amp;rsquo;t worry as the next post will go more in depth
with using Kaldi and look at the &lt;code&gt;gst-kaldi-nnet2-online&lt;/code&gt; plugin,
a plugin to use neural nets with kaldi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>